Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Midvale - Huston Suit 1870-80s. He put up a lot of money for the company and was cheated out of it. A lot of information about the Company, the Facer Patent Suit and on Midvale in general.. (Box 19)
  - Midvale Data on James Facer Patent #271, 823 - On Device to Mgt. Car Wheel Tires 2/6/83 and Facer Suit 1888, 1883-1991 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - James Facer vs. Midvale Steel Co., Germantown Independent, April 1, 1887, July 8, 1887, March 3, 1883, 1883-1887 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - James Facer vs. Midvale Steel Workers April 1, 1887, June 8, 1887, 1883-1887 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - William Butcher Steel Works in Jl. Of Franklin Institute (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - C. Chomienne, "Notes on Steam Hammer" The Railroad and Engineering Journal 1988-1989, 1888-1889 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - C.D. Wrege "Proposed Outline of a Doctoral Dissertation by C.D. Wrege" June 5, 1958 8 pages - Wrege 1958 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Data on Midvale Steel Co. Photos - From Mrs. Hearne - Midvale, Taylor Book, 1886-1989 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Original documents and envelope (with documents and photos)
  - Ron Greenwood - 1987 on Taylor Book Manuscript (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Midvale 1926-1927 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Safety Bulletin Midvale Steel, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Iron and Steel Co. Phila, 1881-1886, 1881-1910 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - 1983 - Origins of Bookkeeping Under the Taylor System - Academy of Mgt. 1983 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Watermarks and Taylor Accounting System 1981 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Richard Strassberg Letter 12/15/1980 on Inability to Copy "Lisbon Bond" on Hathaway Cost System Booklet (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Bookkeeping Under The Taylor System, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - The Historical Origins of "Bookkeeping Under The Taylor System" 1983, 1983-1987 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Basley Search - Taylor Book, 1891-1981 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Notes for Basley-Taylor Bookkeeping Paper 1980-1981, 1885-1981 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - People and Bookkeeping Data for Basley Study 9/18/81, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Front Page of Bookkeeping Under The Taylor System (196B) Showing Hathaway's Remarks, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Mrs. Jane Hartyre Letters on Accting. And Taylor 1981 - Hartyre (Acct), 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - William D. Basley Letter 1893, July 12, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Data Led Analysis of Basley's Bookkeeping System 1981 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Jean Cevasco MA "Fact or Myth - The Taylor System of Accounting" 12-9-1980, 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Bookkeeping Under The Taylor System Analyzed by Kathy Dudas As "Audit Trail" (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Daniel Basley in Newark, NJ 1873, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Basley in NJ 1869-1870 (See Also George Russell File), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Auditors of NY and Erie RR to Check on Basley as Auditor - 2 sheets 10/5/81, Taylor, Whitney, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Basley Data in NYC 1873-1884, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - William D. Basley (Buried at the Evergreens Cemetery, Bushwick Ave and Conway St., Brooklyn, NY 11207, Plot 138, Tulip Grove), 1981- 1982 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Robert Bicknell Cobble Hill Rd., North-RR1, Cobble Hill B.C. VOR ILO - On William D. Basley Photos April 22, 1983 - Taylor and Bookkeeping (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Grand Lodge of F and AM NYC on Basley, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Yonkers Historical Society (On Basley and NYC Northern RR), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - W.D. Basley - NY Providence and Boston RR - 1885-1888, Central RR and Banking Co. of Georgia 1895, 1885-1895 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - General Accting. Data at Stevens - Acct., 1979-1982 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Notes on Taylor Accounting System (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Taylor Accounting System - 1912 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Horace K. Hathaway "The Farrel Foundry and Machine Co." Ansonia, Connecticut: Relative to Cost Numbers 7/8/12, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Cost Keeping Under Taylor System (at Taylor Mgt. Co.) (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Search for Whitney Accounting Reforms for the Navy 1885-1889, Robert B. Matchette Navy and Old Army Branch Military Archives, National Archives - Wash. 20408, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - "F.W. Taylor and Evolution of Standard Overhead Costing" Chen and Pan - 1980 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Taylor System of Bookkeeping, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Basley and Calhoun in Washington, D.C., Whitney and Taylor, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Basley Letter Analysis, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Mgt. Investments and Forest Paper Co. - Use for Basley in Maine, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Frank and Jim Campbell 1978 (On Taylor's Cost System), 1893-1978 (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Projection of Personal Potential 1979, C.D. Wrege (Box 19, Folder 62)
    Manila folder with original documents
  - William D. Basley (Accounting Mgt. Investment Co. 1893) Jean Cevasco 1981 - Taylor, 1893-1981 (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Jean Cevasco Letters - 1981, 1978-1981 (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Early Accounting Books 3/8/81 and William Basley, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Richard Somers Hayes Research Project and Basley, 1893-1983 (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - C.D. Wrege Correspondence, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 67)
    Original documents and copies (in green folder)
  - American Institute of Public Accountants (L. Goodman Letter Re: Basley - July 1981) (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Smith and Furbush Expense Classification 1909 (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Bookkeeping Under Taylor System (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - King Hathaway on Taylor Accounting System, Bulletins of Taylor Society, 1933-1935, 1921-1935 (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - Taylor Bookkeeping System Data, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 72)
  - General Historical Accounting Data on Taylor et al., 1893-1981 (Box 19, Folder 73)
  - 1964 Appliance Accts., 1978 (Box 19, Folder 74)
  - James L. Boockholdt (19th Century RR Accounting, University of Houston), 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 75)
  - Data for Accounting Projects and Marketing Projects, 1927-1980 (Box 19, Folder 76)
  - Steven Solieri 607-757-9268, 2607 Smith Drive, Endwell, NY 13760, Interested in Early History of Cost Accounting, Phoned 12/9/95 - Solieri 1995, 1933-1995 (Box 19, Folder 77)
  - Data on William D. Basley (Died 2/17/1918) in Poor - 1887 as Auditor NY, Providence, Boston RR - Taylor Book, 1893-1983 (Box 19, Folder 78)
  - William C. Whitney Papers and William J. Calhoun Notes 1885 - Accounting and Taylor Book, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 79)
    Original documents and transparency
  - William J. Calhoun - Worked for W.C. Whitney 1885, Born England Feb. 4, 1832, Died NY Oct. 21, 1889 (Box 19, Folder 80)
  - Richard S. Hayes Data (Related to NY and Northern RR, Taylor and Basley) 11/12/82 Basley, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 81)
  - Data from Nat. Eng. Of Nat. Biography on O.H. Payne, L.M. Allen, H.H. Vreeland, A.M. Billings, C.T. Barney - Use for Acct. History, 1945- 1981 (Box 19, Folder 82)
  - RR Accounting NY Public Library, 1891-1913 (Box 19, Folder 83)
  - Edison Papers Project by David Jamison of Rutgers Accounting Dept. 1983 - Study of Edison Accounting Methods (Box 19, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence at Edison Historic Site, West Orange, NJ, On Industrial Lighting 1924 (Compiled by C.D. Wrege 8/23/57), 1957 (Box 19, Folder 85)
  - Edison Laboratory Brochure 1957 (Box 19, Folder 86)
    Original documents (booklets)
  - Bookkeeping Under The Taylor System, 1893-1981 (Box 19, Folder 87)
  - Accounting History 1981 Basley Search, 1934-1981 (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Jean Cevasco's Letter on Basley et al, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 89)
  - Background Material on William D. Basley - Taylor, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Ken Risden's Notes on Data on Accounting at Steven's Institute of Technology April 1981 (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - S.D. Warren Company (re. Basley) - Use for Taylor Accounting System 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Search for W.D. Basley 1984, 1885-1984 (Box 19, Folder 93)
  - Taylor Letters to Chauncey Smith and Edward Sawyer on Basley Accting. System 1892, 1893-1981 (Box 19, Folder 94)
  - Columbia Historical Society (re. Basley and Calhoun), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 95)
  - Zip Kellogg Letters - 1981 Forms for Basley Accting. System, 1893-1981 (Box 19, Folder 96)
  - Marc Jay Epstein - Portion of PhD on Scientific Mgt. and Cost System (Dissertation Univ. Oregon 1973) (Box 19, Folder 97)
- Midvale. Edds Bridge Data (still stands) across the Mississippi to St. Louis. and Charles Harrah, letters from Mrs. Hern who is C. Harrahs great-great granddaughter, who provided the CU photographs of Midvale steel Co. Originals from C. Harrahs per (Box 20)
  - Mrs. Hearne - April 25, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Copies of original documents and original photos
  - Completion of EADS Bridge April 16, 1874 Midvale - Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Research on EADS Bridge of the Mississippi River, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Blue folder with copies of original documents
  - Article on EADS Bridge in St. Louis, Iron Age, Sept. 20, 1928, pp. 683-686, 733-734, Page 686 and 733 on William Butcher Steel Works - Butcher Steel Works (EADS Bridge) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - F.B. Fulky to Charles M. Parker (on EADS Bridge), July 15, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - William Kelly and "Kelly Air Boiling Process for Steel" - Taylor Book, 1887 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Franklin Institute and W. Sellers Data - Midvale, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Bridge, William Sellers and Edgemoor from 1882, 1879-1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Data (East River Bridge) 1879 and Colonel Sellers to 1882 of Midvale Steel - Midvale, 1879-1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Sellers Testimony - 6-22-82, 1882-1987 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - William Sellers in Jl. Of The Franklin Institute, May 1903, pp. 365-381 (By Alexander E. Outerbridge Jr. and Coleman Sellers Jr.) William Sellers - Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Midvale Steel Letter - July 15, 1948 on EADS Bridge Steel (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - William Sellers East River Bridge (Brooklyn Bridge) and Midvale Steel 1882, 1871-1882 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Incorporation Papers Midvale Steel Co. Dec. 14, 1878 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Sellers Family (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Edgemoor Iron Data, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Bridge and Midvale Steel, April 10, 1880 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Articles, 1880 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Data, 1881-1987 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Charles Harrah - President People's Passenger Railway Co., Philadelphia Germantown Independent Gazette - Feb. 4, 1887, 1886- 1889 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Charles Harrah Testimony U.S. Industrial Commission - 1900 Midvale, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Charles J. Harrah - Dict. Of Amer. Biography - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Philadelphia and Reading RR Company's Rolling Mill and Midvale (1877) (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Reading RR Data from Poor's Directory, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Philip Scranton "Mgt. Tapes" 1988 (On Midvale) Letter from Claudia Harris 1988 - Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Data on Midvale from Work Sights by Scranton and Licht - Midvale, 1890-1950 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Midvale Data 1921-1923 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - January 1879 Map of Midvale Steel Works (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - 1877 Plan of Midvale (Box 20, Folder 29)
    Copy of original document (in blue plastic protector)
  - Maps of Midvale in Phila. 1888 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Map of Midvale Steel Works - March 30, 1877, Engineering p. 239 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - 1878 Map of Midvale Steel (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Map of Midvale - Heppenstall Co. 1959 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Midvale Photos (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Map of William Butcher Steel Works, E. Hexamer 1867, 1869-1871, 1867-1871 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Data on Origins of Management in Philadelphia, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Sale of Midvale Steel - Germantown Telegraph, Sept. 1, 1880, p.3 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Germantown Telegraph and Independent Newspapers on Midvale, 1881-1887 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Employees of Midvale Steel Co. Germantown Independent, October 8, 1886 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Patent Drawing of Taylor Steam Hammer - Patent # 424, 939 - 1890 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Samuel Huston vs. E.W. Clark, Sellers and Midvale 1873-1889 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - United States Brewer Assoc. and William Massey, Samuel Huston 1867-1875 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Note from Kathy Drury - 11/25 on Huston Appeal at Jenkins Law Library - Philadelphia (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Samuel Huston Data (related to Midvale), 1988 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Samuel Huston vs. E.W. Clark and William Sellers (Midvale Steel Case, Died August 23 or 24, 1897 Haverford, PA) - Midvale, 1873- 1889 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Samuel Huston Case - Midvale, 1877 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Jenkins Law Library, Phila (9th and Chestnut Streets) Data on Huston Case - Huston, Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Will of Samuel Huston - County of Montgomery, PA, Oct. 12, 1897 - 2 Deeds Huston 1865, 1869 Midvale, 1865-1897 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Addresses of Samuel Huston, Butcher, Aertson, etc. in Gopsill's 1869-1874 Philadelphia (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Samuel Huston Data 10/12/87 - Taylor Book, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Samuel Huston Suit vs. Midvale Steel Co. 1877 - Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Russell Wheeler Davenport (Son of Russell W. Davenport of Midvale and Taylor) Paper in Library of Congress, Taylor Book 1984 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Midvale Steel Property 1880 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Samuel Huston vs. Sellers and Clark, 1882 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Legal Cases - Facer vs. Midvale Steel, Huston vs. Midvale Steel, U.S. Mitis Co. vs. Midvale Steel, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - People Associated with Midvale Steel 1987 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Midvale Steel Co. Formation Papers - Dec. 15, 1880 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Incorporation Papers of Midvale Steel Company Dec. 12, 1880 - Taylor Book, Midvale 1880, 1880-1987 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - Caleb Fox Union Tract Co. of Phila - Related to Charles Harrah and Phila St. NY, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - C. Harrah Telegram to President Roosevelt, 1906 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - Census Records on Charles Harrah, 1880-1988 (Box 20, Folder 61)
  - J.C. Harrah Data (Midvale), 1880-1988 (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - C. Harrah and W.H. Shelmerdine - Midvale, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - Midvale Steel 10/8/86, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - Charles J. Harrah Estate Data from Mrs. Hearne, 1912 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - Charles Harrah Jr. to Florence Harrah Wood, November 1922 (From Mrs. William Hearne) (Box 20, Folder 66)
  - Walter Roberts - Box 44, Lynchburg, VA 24505 - Painting of Steam Hammer at Midvale, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 67)
  - Charles J. Harrah and Peoples Passenger Railway Co., 1883-1988 (Box 20, Folder 68)
  - Gopsill's Philadelphia, 1864-1880 (Box 20, Folder 69)
  - Merriam Feibel and Charles Harrah - Midvale, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 70)
  - Article on Charles Harrah in Philadelphia Bulletin 7-13-58 (from Myers Papers), 1958 (Box 20, Folder 71)
  - Peoples Passenger Ry Co. Officers 1870-1890 (Also Green and Coates Passenger Ry) For Harrah and Midvale (Box 20, Folder 72)
  - Darlene Cecich Letters on Peoples Passenger Ry, Phila and Charles Harrah 1988, 1883-1988 (Box 20, Folder 73)
  - On Charles Harrah and Work People in Phila 1883 (Box 20, Folder 74)
  - Philadelphia Street Ry Co (Use for Charles Harrah and Midvale) 1/5/88, 1882-1885 (Box 20, Folder 75)
  - Data on George F. Work (People's Passenger Ry and Harrah) Phila, 1883-1991 (Box 20, Folder 76)
  - Gopsilll's City Directory of Phila. And Street 1885-1899 (Box 20, Folder 77)
  - William Milnor Roberts (Associated with Charles Harrah 1867), 1890-1956 (Box 20, Folder 78)
  - Charles Harrah and Ency. Of Biography, 1890-1988 (Box 20, Folder 79)
  - William M. Roberts and The Harrah's, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 80)
  - Article on Charles Jefferson Harrah in Midvale Safety Bulletin, June 1932, Vol. 19 #6, pp. 4-7 and p. 15 (Box 20, Folder 81)
  - Charles Harrah and Street Rys. In Philadelphia and Copley Version (Box 20, Folder 82)
  - Charles J. Harrah - Jan 1, 1817 - Feb 18, 1890, 1817-1890 (Box 20, Folder 83)
  - C. Harrah Data (Box 20, Folder 84)
  - Charles Harrah and Philip Bregy Data Midvale, 1965-1988 (Box 20, Folder 85)
  - Charles Harrah Addresses in Philadelphia 1887 (Box 20, Folder 86)
  - Mrs. William L. Hearne (Charles Harrah), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 87)
    Brown folder with original documents and copies
  - Data on Charles J. Harrah for Taylor Book 1988-1990, From Mrs. Hearne 349 Beechwood Rd., Ridgewood, NJ 07450 - 1988-1990 (Box 20, Folder 88)
  - Midvale Photo and Data After 1915 (Box 20, Folder 89)
  - Photos of Midvale (Box 20, Folder 90)
    Copies of original photos
  - Midvale Steel Photos (Box 20, Folder 91)
  - Original list on Photographs of Midvale Steel from Mrs. Hearne 3/1/1989, 3 Pages Plus Maps of Midvale - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 92)
  - Mrs. Hearne's Midvale Photos 1886 Xerox Copies - For Taylor Book (Box 20, Folder 93)
  - List of Photographs from Mrs. Hearne on Midvale 3-1-89, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 94)
  - Midvale Photos from Mrs. Hearne 1989 - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 95)
  - List of Photographs of Midvale Steel at Hagley Museum, 1905 (Box 20, Folder 96)
  - Mrs. Hearne - April 25, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 97)
  - Mrs. Hearne - Sept. 20, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 98)
  - Mrs. Hearne Letters on Midvale and Harrah's, Aug. 5, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 99)
  - Mrs. Hearne Letters 1990 (Box 20, Folder 100)
  - Mrs. Hearne 1991 (Box 20, Folder 101)
  - Mrs. William Hearne - Midvale 1991 Letters (Box 20, Folder 102)
  - Letter to Mrs. Hearne April 18, 1991 - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 103)
  - Mrs. Hearne's Letters 1991, Midvale Research (Box 20, Folder 104)
  - Letter from Mrs. Hearne, Jan. 31, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 105)
  - Mrs. William Hearne Letters 1992 on Midvale (Box 20, Folder 106)
  - News Items on Midvale 1893-1900 - For Midvale Book, 1893-1905 (Box 20, Folder 107)
  - Midvale Steel Records at Stevens 1983, 1893-1983 (Box 20, Folder 108)
  - Michael Riehl Will, January 29, 1875 (Died 12/28/1874 Phila) - Daughter Married Charles Harrah - Harrah History, Midvale, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 109)
  - Michael Riehl Data 1991 (For Mrs. Hearne and Midvale), 1829-1991 (Box 20, Folder 110)
  - M. Riehl's Property Listed on N. 15th Street, Phila - 1870 (Box 20, Folder 111)
  - Individuals and Companies in Philadelphia, 1866-1987 (Box 20, Folder 112)
  - Information on Charles A. Brinley of Midvale from Yale University, 1907-1920 (Box 20, Folder 113)
  - Commonwealth Title Insurance and Trust Co., Phila - Relate to Brinley, 1886-1990 (Box 20, Folder 114)
  - Walter Cross Data 6/12/91 - Chemist for Midvale - Agent for "Gasoline Products Co." and Petroleum Vessels, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 115)
  - Russell W. Davenport Data (Sept. at Midvale to 1886) from Yale University, 1871 (Box 20, Folder 116)
  - Antony C. Sutton on Russell Davenport and Brinley as Members of the Order of Yale 1984 - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 117)
  - Data on Death of Russell Wheeler Davenport, Phil. Inquirer, 3/3/04 p. 7 - Midvale, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 118)
  - George M. Sinclair Midvale 1884, July 1987, 1880-1987 (Box 20, Folder 119)
  - Data on Russell Davenport, 1849-1904 (Box 20, Folder 120)
  - Russell Davenport - Died March 2, 1904, Buried - Church of the Redeemer, Bryn Mawr - Midvale (Box 20, Folder 121)
  - Thomas Durfee Data (Use for Midvale Book 9/25/91) Midvale, 1879 (Box 20, Folder 122)
  - Obituary for Howard C. Myers Jr., Phila. Inquirer, Dec. 20, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 123)
  - James F. Sullivan VP of Midvale, 1926-1987 (Box 20, Folder 124)
  - F.W. Taylor Correspondence at Midvale 1966, 1899-1966 (Box 20, Folder 125)
  - Correspondents of F.W. Taylor at Midvale Steel (1890-1907): T. Coonahan, W.H. Colby, John L. Cox, C.J. Harrah, J. Entwisle, A. Petre, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 126)
    Envelope with originals and copies of documents
  - Midvale Steel Pig-Iron Loading Data 1899 - For Taylor (Box 20, Folder 127)
  - Data on George M. Sinclair (Worked with F.W. Taylor) From Mrs. Hartye - 8/11/87, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 128)
- Canal Museum and Lance Metz Series of 5 Papers CD Wrege gave, along with Ron Greenberg, on Taylor, his Midvale work, his early work at Bethlehem and several articles on FW Taylor and the development of high speed steel, which CD Wrege discovered was ac (Box 21)
  - Bethlehem Steel vs. Niles Bement Pond Case, Records per Bill Kadar - June 24, 1989 - Taylor and Beth. Steel, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Bill Kadar's 6 Sheets on Witnesses for Nile-Bement Pond Case 9/11/89, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Niles-Bement Pond Case - Records at Baymore, NJ 1989 - Later Moved to National Archives, NYC (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. Hartye and Beth v. NBP 1993, 1900-1993 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Lance Metz (Canal Museum) Letters 1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - American Heritage - Article on "F.W. Taylor" Aug/Sept 1979 with Mentor of C.D. Wrege on p. 38 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Lance Metz - Publications, Letters, etc. 1990, 1904-1990 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Lance Metz Letters 1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Lance Metz Nov. 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Lance Metz Nov 15, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Lance Metz 1992, 1981-1993 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Lance Metz and Eastern Symposium March 14, 1992 - Metz 1992 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Lantz Metz 3/15/92, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Lance Metz (Canal Museum) Letters - 1993 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Locktender Newsletter, Fall 1993, Vol XVII, No. 4, see p. 2 on C.D. Wrege Paper on Taylor and High-Speed Steel (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - James Cox, Letters of Charles Harrah of Midvale 1896, File Under Metz 10/18/1993, 1890-1993 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Lance Metz 1994 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - John Fielding (Metallurgist) 1838 Johnston Drive, Bethlehem, PA 18016 Letters, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Lance Metz - 1995 (On 1996 Paper), 1931-1995 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Data on New National Council Museum - 1995 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - F.W. Taylor Forms for Canal Symposium Paper - 2-13-92, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - "Frederick W. Taylor's Early Work at Bethlehem Steel Company: 1898-1899; Some New Insights" For 1993 Canal Museum Symposium, March 20, 1993 - Canal Symposium 1993 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - 35 MM Slides of Noll, Taylor, and 1886 Midvale Photos for Canal Museum Talk 1993 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    Original slides
  - Notes and Pages from Paper on Taylor at Bethlehem for Canal Museum Symposium 1993 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - 1994 Canal Museum Paper on Edmund Lewis 9/1/93, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Taylor Paper - Canal Museum Symposium March 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Transparencies for 3/12/92 Talk at Canal History Symposium on High Heat Discovery - Taylor, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    Transparencies and copies of original documents
  - Notes and Figures for 1994 Canal Symposium Paper, 1900 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Xerox Copies of Manuscript on the Accidental Discovery of the High Speed Steel Proven By Edmund Lewis at Bethlehem Iron Co. in 1898, Paper Given 1994 at Canal Museum Symposium - 1994, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - BVNBP Data for Paper 1994, 1900-1903 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Metz 1994, Locktender Spring 1994 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Locktender - Fall 1994 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Canal Museum Paper 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Photos and Illustrations for 1995 Canal Symposium Paper on F.W. Taylor (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Canal Symposium Paper - On Sale of Taylor White Patent 1995, 1900-1995 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - F.W. Outline for Bethlehem Steel Changes 1898 - For Canal Museum Paper 1997 BVNB (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Information on Charles Brodhead and Robert Lindeman and Taylor BVNB, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Original Paste-Up of 1996 Canal History and Technology Symposium Paper on Taylor and High Speed Steel Patent, 59 Pages, 12/1/95, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 38)